

LEAD LINUX SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR

□ (201) 394-8730 | ■ matt@borlax.com | ★ https://borlax.com | ᡚ github.com/borlax

About_

Skilled technologist with 8+ years experience in Linux Administration and Data Center Operations. Involved in the on-site design, implementation, and management of physical data center environments, as well as administration of VPS and storage environments. Experience in both remote and local administration of systems including virtualization, backups, version control, and monitoring.

Work Experience

The Constant Company, LLC / Vultr, LLC

Remote

LEAD LINUX SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

August 2017 - Present

- Team lead responsible for interviewing, hiring, and training of new System Administrators
- Point of contact and escalation for a 24/7/365 team of 30+ people
- Documenting various tasks and procedures to assist with day to day operations
- · Level 1 customer support of VPS instances, bare metal servers, and other platform features or services
- Level 2 support of critical infrastructure including the troubleshooting of both hardware and software issues
- · Management of VM orchestration and deployment for clients across over 10,000 servers in 25 global locations
- Analysis and mitigation of network attacks and abuse of shared resources
- · Monitoring and management of infrastructure including KVM hypervisors, CEPH backed storage, and internal services
- Coordination with vendors for RMAs and data center staff for install/repair of hardware and infrastructure issues
- · Planning and excuting maintenance windows with various teams, customers, and data center staff

Global Trading Systems, LLC / Strike Technologies

New York, New York

DATA CENTER ENGINEER

December 2015 - August 2017

- · On site installation and management of racks, hardware, and cabling for trading environment in multiple datacenter locations
- OS and application installation via Foreman and Puppet
- Server side configurations of network interfaces, storage mounts, and RAID arrays
- · Collaboration with engineering and software teams during troubleshooting, new service turnup and DR exercises
- · Maintained documentation and standard operating procedures for execution of data center ops
- Documented and managed rack elevations and spare hardware inventory
- · Coordinated remote data center maintenance with remote technicians in various data centers across Europe and Asia
- Network maintenance including Arista and Cisco configurations, cross connect turn up/down, fiber port troubleshooting (light meter, cleaning)
- Communicated with vendors regarding hardware configurations and purchasing, as well as warranty and RMA cases

NASDAQ OMX Carteret, NJ

DATA CENTER TECHNICIAN

February 2013 - December 2015

- Provided data center support for both internal systems/network teams and external customers
- Management of projects including major installations and environment buildouts
- Monitored cabinet power usage and thermals
- · Ran and terminated cross connects between internal routers and customer cabinets and/or cages
- Copper and Fiber testing and fiber cleaning for various intracabinet and intercabinet connections
- · Provided remote hands and eye's support via phone, IM, and email to internal teams and external customers
- Maintained DCIM inventory of all rack elevations and cross connects
- · Continuous monitoring of all server and network hardware

Education

New Jersey Institute of Technology

Newark, NJ

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Class of 2013

References

Furnished upon request.